

Muhammad Moiz Siddique

Phone number: (+92) 3062890575 (Mobile) | Email address:

muhammadmoiz0087@gmail.com | **Website:** https://www.muhammadmoizsiddique.com/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/muhammad-moiz-siddique-b09261252/

Skype: live:muhammadmoiz2000991

Address: Flat no. B-805, Al-minal tower, Block 3A, Gulistan e Johar, 75200, Karachi,

Pakistan (Home)

About me:

I am a passionate and determined candidate who has transformed his hobby into a career, seeking an opportunity with a reputable organisation. I am an accomplished Associate Software Developer with over 5+ years of experience leading projects by acting as an architect, developer and programmer analyst.

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/07/2022 - 30/11/2022

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER BLACK LION INVESTMENT GROUP, INC.

- I'm working as **team lead** on a project, having a **team of 6 peoples**.
- I worked with modern javascript frameworks and libraries such as React IS, Node IS, React Native etc.
- Integrated **third-party tools** and components into applications.
- Developed robust, scalable, modular and API-centric infrastructures.
- Organize a daily **scrum meeting** to identify, prioritize and execute tasks in the software development life cycle
- Manage & update the CI/CD pipeline, review and debug code and working with Docker, AWS and Github Pipeline
- Collaborated with clients to define solution requirements and manage **IIRA** tickets.
- Tested troubleshooting methods and documented resolutions for inclusion in knowledge base for support team
- Implement modern/best programming techniques and infrastructures such as SOLID principles, SaaS, Procedural Programming, Object-oriented Programming, Functional Programming, etc.

07/06/2022 - 31/08/2022 Karachi, Pakistan

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER THE DESIGNRY

- I'm working as team lead on 2 project, having a team of 2 peoples in each project.
- I worked with modern javascript frameworks and libraries such as Angular, React JS, Node JS, etc.
- Integrated **third-party tools** & components and developed robust, scalable, modular and **API-centric infrastructures** application.
- Manage & update the CI/CD pipeline, review and debug code and working with Docker, AWS and Github Pipeline.
- **Tested troubleshooting** methods and documented resolutions for inclusion in knowledge base for support team.
- Developed application servers having scalable, change acceptance, modular and security features.

01/06/2019 - 31/05/2022 Karachi, Pakistan

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER ALGORACK INC.

- Working on Full Stack Technologies such as **Angular**, **React Js**, **Node JS** and others.
- Improved application designs with addition of new features and infrastructure.
- Integrated Build systems for example **Bable** and **Webpacks**.
- Handle API Integration and Wekhooks
- Optimised test cases to maximize success of manual software testing.
- Created successful E2E & Unit test scripts to manage automated feature testing using Jest, Karma, Jasmine, react-testing-tool etc.
- Handle deployments on Cloud platforms such as AWS and Github actions for deployment pipelines.
- Integrate Payment gateways using third party tools such as **Stripe API.**
- Worked with SQL and noSQL databases such as Mongodb, MySQL, SQL server, Postgress SQL.
- Handle client meetings and manage JIRA tickets.
- Completed various project few are from the scratch and I'm the lead developer having a small team to work on.

01/06/2018 - 31/10/2018 Karachi, Pakistan

INTERNSHIP KARACHI PORT TRUST (KPT)

- I worked alongside some of the most skilled programming professionals.
- I learnt (**Dot**) **Net** programming language.
- I was exposed to the software infrastructure used in such a large sized professional company.
- Thoroughly understand how data centers are utilized in such large organizations works.
- This further helped me increase my **team-working creditability** working within a professional IT department and understanding the **workplace dynamic**.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

16/10/2017 - 18/06/2021 Karachi, Pakistan

BACHELOR'S OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE Mohammad Ali Jinnah University

Address Main Shahrah e Faisal, 22-E, Block-6, PECHS, Karachi, Pakistan | Final grade A

2015 - 2017

HIGHER SECONDARY CERTIFICATE Islamia Government Science College

Address Karachi, Sindh, Pakistan | Final grade D

2013 - 2015

SCHOOL SECONDARY CERTIFICATE Habib Public School

Address Karachi, Sindh, Pakistan | Final grade A+

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

PROJECTS

SOCIAL CHAMP (DOT) IO - (https://www.socialchamp.io/) Tech Stack: Angular, Node Js, Mongo db. Responsibilities: Design and develop new modules, maintain and manage existing application including bug fixes, analyze requirement and estimate ETAs.

THINK EVOLVE SOLVE - (https://thinkevolvesolve.ie/) Tech Stack: Angular, Node Js, Azure.

Responsibilities: I'm the **team lead** on this project having **2 members team** to Design, develop and manage frontend, backend and **data pipelines** and **cloud architectures** with **efficient processing** and management of large amounts of data, also **develop interfaces / APIs** for data exchange in Node Js.

Bright Development - (https://bright-development.com/); Tech Stack: **React JS, Node Js, Mongo db.**Responsibilities: **Team lead**, manage daily **workflow**, work on client proposed modules and make sure to provide high quality work, write **test for every new module**, manage and maintain **CI/CD pipeline**, **daily scrum** with team members, handle **client meeting**, manage **JIRA** and assigned work to team.

Black Lion App - (In progress) Tech Stack: React JS, Node Js, Mongo db, Redis, AWS, All Social Media developer APIs, others.

Responsibilities: **Worked from scratch** on this project and i'm the **Team lead**, having a **4 person team** to manage, **esti mate ETAs**, organize a daily **scrum meeting** to identify, prioritize and execute tasks, daily client meeting, understand client stories and assigned work to the team accordingly, manage and maintain **CI/CD pipelines**, using **SaaS** manage to communicate with **cloud services**, review and debug code, manage **Github actions**, update and maintain **story board**, review and merge **pull request** on Github.

HONOURS AND AWARDS

08/06/2022

JavaScript: Core And Advanced Techniques - Udemy: Online Courses

12/08/2020

Speed Programming (Code Jam) - Google

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES AND PLATFORMS

WEB AND APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT

ANGULAR / REACT JS / NODE JS / STENCIL JS / NEST JS / REACT NATIVE / AZURE / AWS / GOOGLE CLOUD / OAUTH / CI-CD PIPELINES / DOCKER / KUBERNETES / AI / GIT / JIRA / BITBUCKET / HEROKU

DATABASE SKILLS

MONGO DB / MY SQL / SQL SERVER / POSTGRESS SQL / REDIS / ORACLE

LANGUAGES

Urdu (Native) / English (Fluent) / Turkish (Basics)